<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Cambodian alphabet is the world's largest alphabet, with 74 letters. The world's shortest alphabet, used in the Solomon Islands, has only 11.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >New York is the city with the biggest population in America. It has over 8.3 million inhabitants.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun's outer layer has a temperature of 6,000C . Inside the sun the temperature is 15,000,000 C.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Population of the Earth is about 6,800,000,000 (6.80 billion) people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Sound travels at a speed of around 767 miles per hour (1,230 kilometres per hour).</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alexander Graham Bell is credited with inventing the first telephone in 1876.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >If you could travel from Earth to the Sun in a plane it would take you 17 years</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The earliest dated printed book is the "Diamond Sutra", printed in China almost 3,000 thousand years ago.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >About two thirds of the Earth's surface is covered with water.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's oldest person was Kama Chinen. She lived in Japan and died a week before her 115th birthday.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first powered, sustained, and controlled flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903. In 1919 the First transatlantic flight was made.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On 12 April 1961 Yuri Alekseyevich Gagarin, a Soviet cosmonaut , became the first human in outer space and the first to orbit the Earth. He became a hero of the Soviet Union for his pioneering tour in space.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The closest planet to earth is Venus.  It would take over 4 years to travel there by plane.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
  </item>
</items>
