<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The average distance from the earth to the Sun is 150 million kilometers (93 million miles). If you could travel from Earth to the Sun in a plane it would take you 17 years</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Cheetah is the fastest land animal. It can run at 112 kilometres per hour (70 mph). The average person can run from 12 - 17 miles an hour in sprints, so keep away from cheetahs.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alaska is the largest state in America.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The lowest temperature ever recorded world was at Vostok Station, Antarctica on the 21 July 1983. it was a bitter -89.6C</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The moon is just over one quarter the size of the earth.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortfin Mako shark is the fastest fish, it can swim at 50 kilometres per hour. Olympic gold-medal swimmers could not escape even if they tried, they can only swim at 8 kph (5 mph) .</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Population of the Earth is about 6,800,000,000 (6.80 billion) people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >New York is the city with the biggest population in America. It has over 8.3 million inhabitants. Los Angeles is in second place. It has 3.8 million people.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Elephants demonstrate concern for members of their families they take care of weak or injured members and appear to grieve over a dead companion.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >China has more than 350 million telephones, the most of any other country. The United States is second with 268 million.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The moon orbits the Earth every 27.32 days</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The South Pole is the least sunny placeon earth with only 182 days a year off sunshine</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale can produce sounds up to 188 decibels. This is the loudest sound produced by a living animal and has been detected as far away as 530 miles.</value>
  </item>
</items>
