<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alaska is the largest state in America.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The lowest temperature ever recorded world was at Vostok Station, Antarctica on the 21 July 1983. it was a bitter -89.6C</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Sneezing with your eyes open is impossible</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest woman was Zeng Jinlian. She was 2.48 meters ( 8ft 2in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sputnik 1, launched on October 4, 1957 by Russia, was the first human-made object to orbit the Earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Michael Jackson's  1982 Thriller album is the biggest seller of all time. Over 110 millions albums were sold.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest recorded flight of a chicken is thirteen seconds</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Diamonds are the hardest substance known to man. A diamond is 58 times harder than the next hardest mineral on earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Jean Pilatre de Rozier ( a Frenchman ) made the first balloon flight, reaching a peak altitude of about 500 ft, and traveling about 51/2 mi in 20 min.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >A sneeze generates a wind of 166 km/hr (100 mi/hr), and a cough moves out at 100 km/hr (60 mi/hr).</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Steve Wozniak designed the first Apple computer in 1976. It was known as the Apple I.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Elephants demonstrate concern for members of their families they take care of weak or injured members and appear to grieve over a dead companion.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's oldest person was Kama Chinen. She lived in Japan and died a week before her 115th birthday.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >A sneeze generates a wind of 166 km/hr (100 mi/hr), and a cough moves out at 100 km/hr (60 mi/hr).</value>
  </item>
</items>
