<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The South Pole is the least sunny placeon earth with only 182 days a year off sunshine</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Sebastien Lenormand was first to demonstrate the parachute. In Missouri 1912, Captain Berry was the first to jump from a plane with a parachute.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The strongest wind ever recorded wind was on Mt Washington, New Hampshire, USA. It was an amazing 231mph.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On July 20, 1969, Neil Armstrong became the first human to step on the moon.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Jean Pilatre de Rozier ( a Frenchman ) made the first balloon flight, reaching a peak altitude of about 500 ft, and traveling about 51/2 mi in 20 min.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The closest planet to earth is Venus.  It would take over 4 years to travel there by plane.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are more than 2,700 languages ( + more than 7,000 dialects) in the world. More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >About two thirds of the Earth's surface is covered with water.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Spine-tailed Swift is the fastest bird. It can fly at 170 kilometres per hour (105mph). The Peregrine Falcon is the fastest bird that dives headfirst down through the sky. They can travel at up to 200mph.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in northern and south-western China. English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Population of the Earth is about 6,800,000,000 (6.80 billion) people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >In the Summer of 1896 the first modern Olympics was held in Athens, Greece. The 2012 Olympics will be held in London.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortest person in the world is Khagendra Thapa Maga. He is 56 cm ( 22 in ) tall. The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
  </item>
</items>
