<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >A sneeze generates a wind of 166 km/hr (100 mi/hr), and a cough moves out at 100 km/hr (60 mi/hr).</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The original Olympic Games were a series of athletic competitions held in Ancient Greece.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Intel introduces the first microprocessor, the Intel 4004 on November 15, 1971.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest woman was Zeng Jinlian. She was 2.48 meters ( 8ft 2in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Johannes Gutenberg invented the printing press in 1436 . Gutenberg is also accredited with printing the world's first book known as the Gutenberg Bible.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The creator of the first working light bulb was Joseph Wilson Swan. Thomas Edison improved on Swan's design by using a better incandescent material and a higher vacuum.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >In the Summer of 1896 the first modern Olympics was held in Athens, Greece. The 2012 Olympics will be held in London.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The earth is the 3rd planet from the sun and is the 5th largest planet in our solar system. Jupiter is the largest planet.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world. It is 828 meters ( 2,717 ft ) tall.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >A shark can hear a fish in the water from more than a mile away.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The biggest earthquake ever recorded occurred in Chile, in 1960. It measured 9.5 on the Richter scale.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The original Olympic Games were a series of athletic competitions held in Ancient Greece. In the Summer of 1896 the first modern Olympics was held in Athens, Greece. The 2012 Olympics will be held in London.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount McKinley in Alaska in the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On 12 April 1961 Yuri Alekseyevich Gagarin, a Soviet cosmonaut , became the first human in outer space and the first to orbit the Earth. He became a hero of the Soviet Union for his pioneering tour in space.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Population of the Earth is about 6,800,000,000 (6.80 billion) people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Atari releases Pong, the first commercial video game on November 29, 1972.</value>
  </item>
</items>
