<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Atari releases Pong, the first commercial video game on November 29, 1972.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Jean Pilatre de Rozier ( a Frenchman ) made the first balloon flight, reaching a peak altitude of about 500 ft, and traveling about 51/2 mi in 20 min.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >House flies have a lifespan of two weeks.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >If you travelled to the Moon in a plane it would take about 16 days. It takes 3 days in a spaceship to get there.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is young in comparison, it is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On July 20, 1969, Neil Armstrong became the first human to step on the moon. He, Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin and Michael Collins were the crew of Apollo 11.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in China.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale can produce the loudest sound of any living animal. The sound can be detected as far away as 530 miles.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Mount McKinley in Alaska is the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high. Alaska is also the largest state in America, it is 656,425 square miles in size.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world. It is 828 meters ( 2,717 ft ) tall.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Cambodian alphabet is the world's largest alphabet, with 74 letters.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
</items>
