<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The launch of the Russian Spiknit 1 spcecraft started the 'space race' between Russia and America. Explorer 1 was the first spacecraft launched by the United States on 31 January 1958.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Tides are caused by the rotation of the Earth and the gravitational effects of the Moon and Sun.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Chinese invented eyeglasses. Marco Polo reported seeing many pairs worn by the Chinese as early as 1275, 500 years before lens griding became an art in the West.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The first 'talkie' movie was Al Jolson's The Jazz Singer released in 1927.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Electric eels can stun both predators and prey with electric shocks of around 500 volts.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun's outer layer has a temperature of 6,000C . Inside the sun the temperature is 15,000,000 C.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >A shark can hear a fish in the water from more than a mile away.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics was won by Albert Einstein for his work in the field of theoretical physics.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The lowest temperature ever recorded world was at Vostok Station, Antarctica on the 21 July 1983. it was a bitter -89.6C</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On April 30, 1789, George Washington became the first President of the United States.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The heaviest apple weighed 1.849 kg (4 lb 1 oz) and was grown and picked by Chisato Iwasaki at his apple farm in Hirosaki City, Japan October 24, 2005.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >If you could travel from Earth to the Sun in a plane it would take you 17 years</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The moon is 384,400 km from earth. If you travelled to the Moon in a plane it would take about 16 days. It takes 3 days in a spaceship to get there.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
  </item>
</items>
