<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 195 countries in the world and there are more than 2,700 languages.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alaska is the largest state in America.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first powered, sustained, and controlled flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903. In 1919 the First transatlantic flight was made.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >House flies have a lifespan of two weeks.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortest person in the world is Khagendra Thapa Maga. He is 56 cm ( 22 in ) tall. The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest earthquake ever recorded occurred in Chile, in 1960. Known as the Great Chilean Earthquake, the quake measured 9.5 on the Richter scale.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are more than 2,700 languages  in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Electric eels can stun both predators and prey with electric shocks of around 500 volts.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortest person in the world is Khagendra Thapa Maga. He is 56 cm ( 22 in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are around 2000 different plant types that humans use as food.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Steve Wozniak designed the first Apple computer in 1976. It was known as the Apple I.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 206 bones in the adult human body and are 300 in children. As children age some bones fuse together.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On July 20, 1969, Neil Armstrong became the first human to step on the moon. He, Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin and Michael Collins were the crew of Apollo 11.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
</items>
