<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Pacific Ocean is the largest ocean in the world. It covers about 1/3 of its surface.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest earthquake ever recorded occurred in Chile, in 1960. Known as the Great Chilean Earthquake, the quake measured 9.5 on the Richter scale.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in China.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Cheetah is the fastest land animal. It can run at 112 kilometres per hour (70 mph). The average person can run from 12 - 17 miles an hour in sprints, so keep away from cheetahs.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount McKinley in Alaska in the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics was won by Albert Einstein for his work in the field of theoretical physics.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest recorded flight of a chicken is thirteen seconds</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The city with the largest population is Shanghai in China. It has almost 14 million inhabitants.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 9 planets that circle the sun. They are divided into two groups: the inner planets (Mercury, Venus,Earth, and Mars) and the outer planets (Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto).</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Cambodian alphabet is the world's largest alphabet, with 74 letters.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The moon is 384,400 km from earth. If you travelled to the Moon in a plane it would take about 16 days. It takes 3 days in a spaceship to get there.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >About two thirds of the Earth's surface is covered with water.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The closest planet to earth is Venus. It is about 38 million kilometers away. It would take over 4 years to travel there by plane.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale can produce sounds up to 188 decibels. This is the loudest sound produced by a living animal and has been detected as far away as 530 miles.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortfin Mako shark is the fastest fish, it can swim at 50 kilometres per hour. Olympic gold-medal swimmers could not escape even if they tried, they can only swim at 8 kph (5 mph) .</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in northern and south-western China. English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
  </item>
</items>
