<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The first 'talkie' movie was Al Jolson's The Jazz Singer released in 1927.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The city with the largest population is Shanghai in China. It has almost 14 million inhabitants.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are more than 2,700 languages in the world. There are also more than 7,000 dialects. A dialect is a regional language variation with different pronunciation, vocabulary, or meaning.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Most people blink about 17,000 times a day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On 12 April 1961 Yuri Alekseyevich Gagarin, a Soviet cosmonaut , became the first human in outer space and the first to orbit the Earth. He became a hero of the Soviet Union for his pioneering tour in space.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Roughly 70 percent of an adult's body is made up of water.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in China.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Steve Wozniak designed the first Apple computer in 1976. It was known as the Apple I.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The earth is the 3rd planet from the sun and is the 5th largest planet in our solar system.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Tides are caused by the rotation of the Earth and the gravitational effects of the Moon and Sun.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are more than 2,700 languages  in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1972 Ray Tomlinson at BBN developed the first e-mail program. In his first email to himself, he uses the @ sign. This was the first time it appeared in an e-mail address.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The biggest earthquake ever recorded occurred in Chile, in 1960. It measured 9.5 on the Richter scale.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun is one of about 200 billion stars in the Milky Way galaxy. The most current estimates guess that there are 100 to 200 billion galaxies in the Universe</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The explosion of Mount Tambora, on Sumbawa island, Indonesia in 1815 was heard 2,600 km (1,600 mi) away and has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
  </item>
</items>
