<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >New York is the city with the biggest population in America. It has over 8.3 million inhabitants. Los Angeles is in second place. It has 3.8 million people.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Sneezing with your eyes open is impossible</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Yuma in the state of Arizona has over 4,000 hours of sunshine per year - making it the sunniest place on the planet. The South Pole is the least sunny place with only 182 days a year off sunshine</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun is one of about 200 billion stars in the Milky Way galaxy. The most current estimates guess that there are 100 to 200 billion galaxies in the Universe</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's shortest alphabet, used in the Solomon Islands, has only 11.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The creator of the first working light bulb was Joseph Wilson Swan. Thomas Edison improved on Swan's design by using a better incandescent material and a higher vacuum.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortfin Mako shark is the fastest fish, it can swim at 50 kilometres per hour. Olympic gold-medal swimmers could not escape even if they tried, they can only swim at 8 kph (5 mph) .</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The elephant is distinguished by its high level of intelligence, interesting behavior, methods of communication and complex social structure.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Elephants demonstrate concern for members of their families they take care of weak or injured members and appear to grieve over a dead companion.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sputnik 1, launched on October 4, 1957 by Russia, was the first human-made object to orbit the Earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Johannes Gutenberg invented the printing press in 1436 . Gutenberg is also accredited with printing the world's first book known as the Gutenberg Bible.</value>
  </item>
</items>
