<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On July 20, 1969, Neil Armstrong became the first human to step on the moon.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are 195 countries in the world and there are more than 2,700 languages.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Mount McKinley in Alaska is the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high. Alaska is also the largest state in America, it is 656,425 square miles in size.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1932 Amelia Earhart became the first woman to do a solo transatlantic flight. She flew from Harbor Grace, Newfoundland, to Ireland in approximately 15 hr.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount McKinley in Alaska in the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The world's oldest person was Kama Chinen. She lived in the Japanese island of Okinawa. She died a week before her 115th birthday. She was born on May 10, 1895.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >A shark can hear a fish in the water from more than a mile away.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in China.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Intel introduces the first microprocessor, the Intel 4004 on November 15, 1971.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are around 2000 different plant types that humans use as food.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's population grows by over 100 million each year.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Roughly 70 percent of an adult's body is made up of water.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Atari releases Pong, the first commercial video game on November 29, 1972.</value>
  </item>
</items>
