<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >If you travelled to the Moon in a plane it would take about 16 days. It takes 3 days in a spaceship to get there.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Drinking too much water too quickly can lead to water intoxication which causes an imbalance of water in the brain</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Roughly 70 percent of an adult's body is made up of water.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Mount McKinley in Alaska is the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high. Alaska is also the largest state in America, it is 656,425 square miles in size.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest word in a major English dictionary is 'Pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovolcanoconiosis'.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Atari releases Pong, the first commercial video game on November 29, 1972.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >In the Summer of 1896 the first modern Olympics was held in Athens, Greece. The 2012 Olympics will be held in London.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The tallest building in America is the Willius Tower in Chicago.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest woman was Zeng Jinlian. She was 2.48 meters ( 8ft 2in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1972 Ray Tomlinson at BBN developed the first e-mail program. In his first email to himself, he uses the @ sign. This was the first time it appeared in an e-mail address.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is young in comparison, it is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >John Logie Baird was the inventor of the world's first working television system in Hastings, England in 1923.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On 12 April 1961 Yuri Alekseyevich Gagarin, a Soviet cosmonaut , became the first human in outer space and the first to orbit the Earth. He became a hero of the Soviet Union for his pioneering tour in space.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun's outer layer has a temperature of 6,000C . Inside the sun the temperature is 15,000,000 C.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The closest planet to earth is Venus.  It would take over 4 years to travel there by plane.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 9 planets that circle the sun. They are divided into two groups: the inner planets (Mercury, Venus,Earth, and Mars) and the outer planets (Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto).</value>
  </item>
</items>
