<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's shortest alphabet, used in the Solomon Islands, has only 11.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Light travels slower through different substances such as glass, water and air.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Cheetah is the fastest land animal. Cheetahs can run much faster than people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 9 planets that circle the sun. They are divided into two groups: the inner planets (Mercury, Venus,Earth, and Mars) and the outer planets (Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto).</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortest person in the world is Khagendra Thapa Maga. He is 56 cm ( 22 in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The most widely spoken language is Mandarin, nearly 1 billion people speak it, mainly in northern and south-western China. English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's population grows by over 100 million each year.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Population of the Earth is about 6,800,000,000 (6.80 billion). China has the most people, its population is 1.3 billion.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The moon orbits the Earth every 27.32 days</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Pacific Ocean is the largest ocean in the world. It covers about 1/3 of its surface.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The strongest wind ever recorded wind was on Mt Washington, New Hampshire, USA. It was an amazing 231mph.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The South Pole is the least sunny placeon earth with only 182 days a year off sunshine</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The moon orbits the Earth every 27.32 days</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >China has more than 350 million telephones, the most of any other country. The United States is second with 268 million.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun's outer layer has a temperature of 6,000C . Inside the sun the temperature is 15,000,000 C.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Cambodian alphabet is the world's largest alphabet, with 74 letters.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Michael Jackson's  1982 Thriller album is the biggest seller of all time. Over 110 millions albums were sold.</value>
  </item>
</items>
