<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Opened in 2010, the Burj Khalifa in Dubai is the tallest building in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The longest word in a major English dictionary is 'Pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovolcanoconiosis'. It is 45 characters long.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are more than 2,700 languages  in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Surface Area of the earth is 197 million square miles, about two thirds of the Earth's surface is covered with water.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are more than 2,700 languages in the world. There are also more than 7,000 dialects. A dialect is a regional language variation with different pronunciation, vocabulary, or meaning.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Tides are caused by the rotation of the Earth and the gravitational effects of the Moon and Sun.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The longest recorded flight of a chicken is thirteen seconds</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Jean Pilatre de Rozier ( a Frenchman ) made the first balloon flight, reaching a peak altitude of about 500 ft, and traveling about 51/2 mi in 20 min.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The first 'talkie' movie was Al Jolson's The Jazz Singer released in 1927.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortfin Mako shark is the fastest fish.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The elephant is distinguished by its high level of intelligence, interesting behavior, methods of communication and complex social structure.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The explosion of Mount Tambora, on Sumbawa island, Indonesia in 1815 was heard 2,600 km (1,600 mi) away and has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The closest planet to earth is Venus.  It would take over 4 years to travel there by plane.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Microsoft Windows was announced November 10, 1983.</value>
  </item>
</items>
