<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The longest word in a major English dictionary is 'Pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovolcanoconiosis'. It is 45 characters long.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The launch of the Russian Spiknit 1 spcecraft started the 'space race' between Russia and America. Explorer 1 was the first spacecraft launched by the United States on 31 January 1958.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >In the Summer of 1896 the first modern Olympics was held in Athens, Greece. The 2012 Olympics will be held in London.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The creator of the first working light bulb was Joseph Wilson Swan. Thomas Edison improved on Swan's design by using a better incandescent material and a higher vacuum.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale can produce the loudest sound of any living animal. The sound can be detected as far away as 530 miles.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >On April 30, 1789, George Washington became the first President of the United States.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On average, Elephants sleep for about 2 hours per day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The average distance from the earth to the Sun is 150 million kilometers (93 million miles). If you could travel from Earth to the Sun in a plane it would take you 17 years</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alexander Graham Bell is credited with inventing the first telephone in 1876.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Diamonds are the hardest substance known to man. A diamond is 58 times harder than the next hardest mineral on earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Alaska is the largest state in America.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Intel introduces the first microprocessor, the Intel 4004 on November 15, 1971.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The biggest planet in the Solar System is Jupiter. It is 317 times as heavy as the earth</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are more than 2,700 languages ( + more than 7,000 dialects) in the world. More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's shortest alphabet, used in the Solomon Islands, has only 11.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun's outer layer has a temperature of 6,000C . Inside the sun the temperature is 15,000,000 C.</value>
  </item>
</items>
