<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Most people blink about 17,000 times a day.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The creator of the first working light bulb was Joseph Wilson Swan.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The world's population grows by over 100 million each year.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The first letter of every continent's name is the same as the last: AmericA, AntarcticA, EuropE, AsiA, AustraliA, AfricA.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The first 'talkie' movie was Al Jolson's The Jazz Singer released in 1927.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The explosion of Mount Tambora in Indonesia in 1815 has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Michael Jackson's  1982 Thriller album is the biggest seller of all time. Over 110 millions albums were sold.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The South Pole is the least sunny placeon earth with only 182 days a year off sunshine</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Sun is one of about 200 billion stars in the Milky Way galaxy. The most current estimates guess that there are 100 to 200 billion galaxies in the Universe</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >In 1783 Jean Pilatre de Rozier ( a Frenchman ) made the first balloon flight, reaching a peak altitude of about 500 ft, and traveling about 51/2 mi in 20 min.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >On July 20, 1969, Neil Armstrong became the first human to step on the moon.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The explosion of Mount Tambora, on Sumbawa island, Indonesia in 1815 was heard 2,600 km (1,600 mi) away and has been called the loudest sound ever heard by humans.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortfin Mako shark is the fastest fish.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Tides are caused by the rotation of the Earth and the gravitational effects of the Moon and Sun.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are around 2000 different plant types that humans use as food.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Spine-tailed Swift is the fastest bird. It can fly at 170 kilometres per hour (105mph). The Peregrine Falcon is the fastest bird that dives headfirst down through the sky. They can travel at up to 200mph.</value>
  </item>
</items>
