<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount McKinley in Alaska in the highest mountain in America. It is 20,320 ft high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Gravity keeps Earth and the other planets in our solar system in orbit around the Sun. It also keeps the Moon in orbit around Earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The creator of the first working light bulb was Joseph Wilson Swan.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics was won by Albert Einstein for his work in the field of theoretical physics.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Universe is about 14 billion years old. The earth is young in comparison, it is only 4.6 billion years old.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. The second largest animal is the Afican elephant.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 9 planets that circle the sun. They are divided into two groups: the inner planets (Mercury, Venus,Earth, and Mars) and the outer planets (Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto).</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Cheetah is the fastest land animal. Cheetahs can run much faster than people.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Chinese invented eyeglasses. Marco Polo reported seeing many pairs worn by the Chinese as early as 1275, 500 years before lens griding became an art in the West.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Michael Jackson's  1982 Thriller album is the biggest seller of all time. Over 110 millions albums were sold.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are 9 planets that circle the sun.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 195 countries in the world and there are more than 2,700 languages.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Mount Everest is the tallest mountain in the world. It is 8850 meters (29035ft) high.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Steve Wozniak designed the first Apple computer in 1976. It was known as the Apple I.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The world's oldest person was Kama Chinen. She lived in Japan and died a week before her 115th birthday.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The shortest person in the world is Khagendra Thapa Maga. He is 56 cm ( 22 in ) tall. The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The blue whale can produce the loudest sound of any living animal. The sound can be detected as far away as 530 miles.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Microsoft Windows was announced November 10, 1983.</value>
  </item>
</items>
