<items>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Roughly 70 percent of an adult's body is made up of water.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The longest river is the Nile. It is 6,650 Km ( 4,132 miles ) long. It flows into the Mediterranean Sea.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The Amazon is the second longest river. It is 6.400 km ( 4,000 miles ) long. It flows into the Atlantic ocean.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Intel introduces the first microprocessor, the Intel 4004 on November 15, 1971.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The earth is the 3rd planet from the sun and is the 5th largest planet in our solar system.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The Cheetah is the fastest land animal. It can run at 112 kilometres per hour (70 mph). The average person can run from 12 - 17 miles an hour in sprints, so keep away from cheetahs.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >English is the second most spoken language in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The world's population grows by over 100 million each year.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >About two thirds of the Earth's surface is covered with water.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are 195 countries in the world and there are more than 2,700 languages.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >There are more than 2,700 languages  in the world.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The banana tree is not actually a tree, it is a herb. It bears fruit once a year and then dies.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest woman was Zeng Jinlian. She was 2.48 meters ( 8ft 2in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >The blue whale is the largest known animal on Earth. Mature blue whales can measure anywhere from 75 feet (23 m) to 100 feet (30.5 m) long and can weigh as much as 150 tons.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The shortest woman was Pauline Muster. She was 58 cm ( 23 in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >New York is the city with the biggest population in America. It has over 8.3 million inhabitants. Los Angeles is in second place. It has 3.8 million people.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >The tallest person in the world was Robert Wadlow. He was 2.72 meters ( 8ft 11in ) tall.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >Gravity keeps Earth and the other planets in our solar system in orbit around the Sun. It also keeps the Moon in orbit around Earth.</value>
  </item>
  <item>
      <value grade="1,2" >Orville and Wilbur Wright achieved the first flight of an airplane.on the morning of December 17, 1903.</value>
      <value grade="3,4,5" >There are more than 2,700 languages ( + more than 7,000 dialects) in the world. More than 1,000 different languages are spoken on the continent of Africa.</value>
  </item>
</items>
